Welcome to Predator Prey Grass
a multi agent simulation where survival
competition
and evolution play out in a dynamic digital ecosystem
In this grid world
two types of agents roam the environment
Red circles are predators and blue diamonds are prey
Green squares that's grass
the food source for prey And those arrows
they show each agent's direction of movement
Predators hunt prey pray
search for grass
Both learn to optimize their behavior using multi agent
reinforcement learning
a type of artificial intelligence
powered by neural networks
At first agents know nothing
They move randomly
driven only by the chance of reproduction
Reproduction happens when agents collect enough energy
by eating But be warned
energy is consumed with every move
and when energy runs out they die
Initially all agents can only move one step at a time
This creates a delicate balance
a dynamic tug of war between predators and prey
But evolution is in play With every reproduction
there's a tiny chance for mutation
creating a child that can move faster
These faster offspring gain a competitive edge
reaching prey
or grass more efficiently than their slower peers
Over time the trait spreads
You'll notice darker colored agents taking over
These are the faster mutants
Even with only a small chance of mutation
and equal odds of reverting to slow
the faster agents begin to dominate
No one tells agents what to do
Through rewards and consequences
they learn how to survive
What emerges is an open ended Evolutionary dance
complex unpredictable and endlessly fascinating
Curious to explore more Check out the Github repository
to see the code behind this evolving world
and maybe help shape the next emergent trait