Welcome to Predator Prey Grass
a multi agent simulation where survival
competition
and evolution unfold in a dynamic digital ecosystem
In this grid world
two types of agents roam the environment
Red circles represent predators
and blue diamonds represent prey
The green non moving squares represent grass
the primary food source for prey
Agents need energy to stay alive
Predators hunt prey
and prey search for grass in order to survive
Ultimately agents are rewarded when they reproduce
To achieve this they learn to optimize their movement
using multi agent reinforcement learning
a type of artificial intelligence
powered by neural networks
Reproduction
occurs only when agents collect enough energy
through eating Initially
all agents can only move one step at a time
This creates a delicate balance
a dynamic tug of war between predators and prey
But evolution is in play With every reproduction
there's a tiny chance of mutation
creating offspring that can move faster
These faster individuals gain a competitive edge
reaching prey or grass
more efficiently than their slower peers
Over time the trait spreads
You'll notice darker colored agents taking over
These are the faster mutants
Even with only a small chance of mutation
and equal odds of reverting to slow
the faster agents begin to dominate
the populations of both predators
and prey
This is a combination of Learned behavior
and genetic adaptation
Through rewards and consequences
agents learn how to survive
What emerges is an open ended evolutionary arms race
complex unpredictable and endlessly Fascinating
Curious to explore more Check out the Github repository
to see the code behind this evolving world
and maybe help shape the next emergent trait